University of Connecticut
© 2006 University of Connecticut
University of Connecticut, Cabinet Records.
1979-1990
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center
University of Connecticut, Office of the President.
5.5 linear feet
MSS19980161
Minutes of meetings between the President and Vice Presidents of the University.
History
The office of the President was established in 1893 when the state of Connecticut established Storrs Agricultural College as Connecticut's land-grant institution of higher education. At that time the title of its chief administrative officer, Benjamin F. Koons, was changed from Principal of the former Storrs Agricultural School to President of the new college.
When Connecticut State College became the University of Connecticut in 1939, the new laws and By-laws stated that, "the President of the University is the executive and administrative officer of the Board [of Trustees]. In this capacity he is responsible for the operations of the University and is given authority requisite to that end." This is the mandate under which President Jorgensen worked throughout his long service as President of the University. The President was also designated as "chairman of the University Senate and of the several schools and colleges." The administrative reorganization authorized by President Jorgensen for the University in 1939 placed direct responsibility for the schools and colleges. President Jorgensen was thus able to devote all his energies chiefly to the fulfillment of his plans for the overall development of the University.
The documents in this collection were created during the presidential tenures of John A. DiBiaggio and Anthony DiBenedetto.
More information on the President's Office records is available here.
Scope and Content
The collection contains a sequential series of minutes documenting the issues, concerns and activities of the President and Vice Presidents of the University from 1985 through 1990. An index to the minutes covering the years 1979-1985 is included.
Arrangement
The minutes are arranged chronologically.
Series I: Minutes ( 1979-1990 ) includes meeting minutes and occasional memoranda. A portion of the minutes have been indexed.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Organizations:
University of Connecticut. Office of the President.; University of Connecticut.
Places:
Storrs (Conn.)
Subjects:
Universities and colleges--Administration.; Storrs (Conn.)--Education Universities and Colleges.
Document Types:
Minutes.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was transferred by the President's Office at an unknown date.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Series I: Minutes, 1979-1990
  - Index to Minutes, 1979 July 25 - 1985 March 20 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Minutes
    - 1979 July 25 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
    - 1979 August 1 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
    - 1979 August 8 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - 1979 August 15 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - 1979 August 22 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - 1979 September 5 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
    - 1979 September 19 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
    - 1979 October 2 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
    - 1979 October 17 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
    - 1979 October 24 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
    - 1979 October 30 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
    - 1979 November 7 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
    - 1979 November 14 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
    - 1979 December 4 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
    - 1979 December 12 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
    - 1979 December 19 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
    - 1980 January 2 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
    - 1980 January 9 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
    - 1980 January 16 (Box 1:, Folder 20)
    - 1980 January 23 (Box 1:, Folder 21)
    - 1980 January 30 (Box 1:, Folder 22)
    - 1980 February 7 (Box 1:, Folder 23)
    - 1980 February 13 (Box 1:, Folder 24)
    - 1980 February 28 (Box 1:, Folder 25)
    - 1980 March 5 (Box 2:, Folder 26)
    - 1980 March 12 (Box 2:, Folder 27)
    - 1980 March 18 (Box 2:, Folder 28)
    - 1980 March 26 (Box 2:, Folder 29)
    - 1980 April 2 (Box 2:, Folder 30)
    - 1980 April 9 (Box 2:, Folder 31)
    - 1980 April 16 (Box 2:, Folder 32)
    - 1980 April 23 (Box 2:, Folder 33)
    - 1980 April 29 (Box 2:, Folder 34)
    - 1980 May 7 (Box 2:, Folder 35)
    - 1980 May 20 (Box 2:, Folder 36)
    - 1980 May 28 (Box 2:, Folder 37)
    - 1980 June 4 (Box 2:, Folder 38)
    - 1980 June 11 (Box 2:, Folder 39)
    - 1980 July 1 (Box 2:, Folder 40)
    - 1980 July 16 (Box 2:, Folder 41)
    - 1980 August 13 (Box 2:, Folder 42)
    - 1980 August 27 (Box 2:, Folder 43)
    - 1980 September 3 (Box 2:, Folder 44)
    - 1980 September 9 (Box 2:, Folder 45)
    - 1980 September 16 (Box 2:, Folder 46)
    - 1980 September 24 (Box 2:, Folder 47)
    - 1980 October 1 (Box 2:, Folder 48)
    - 1980 October 6 (Box 3:, Folder 49)
    - 1980 October 15 (Box 3:, Folder 50)
    - 1980 October 22 (Box 3:, Folder 51)
    - 1980 October 29 (Box 3:, Folder 52)
    - 1980 November 4 (Box 3:, Folder 53)
    - 1980 November 11 (Box 3:, Folder 54)
    - 1980 November 20 (Box 3:, Folder 55)
    - 1980 November 26 (Box 3:, Folder 56)
    - 1980 December 5 (Box 3:, Folder 57)
    - 1980 December 17 (Box 3:, Folder 58)
    - 1980 December 23 (Box 3:, Folder 59)
    - 1981 January 5 (Box 3:, Folder 60)
    - 1981 January 7 (Box 3:, Folder 61)
    - 1981 January 14 (Box 3:, Folder 62)
    - 1981 January 21 (Box 3:, Folder 63)
    - 1981 January 28 (Box 3:, Folder 64)
    - 1981 February 4 (Box 3:, Folder 65)
    - 1981 Febuary 11 (Box 3:, Folder 66)
    - 1981 February 18 (Box 3:, Folder 67)
    - 1981 February 24 (Box 3:, Folder 68)
    - 1981 March 4 (Box 3:, Folder 69)
    - 1981 March 9 (Box 4:, Folder 70)
    - 1981 March 16 (Box 4:, Folder 71)
    - 1981 March 23 (Box 4:, Folder 72)
    - 1981 April 1 (Box 4:, Folder 73)
    - 1981 April 6 (Box 4:, Folder 73a)
    - 1981 April 13 (Box 4:, Folder 74)
    - 1981 April 14 (Box 4:, Folder 75)
    - 1981 April 20 (Box 4:, Folder 76)
    - 1981 April 29 (Box 4:, Folder 77)
    - 1981 May 6 (Box 4:, Folder 78)
    - 1981 May 13 (Box 4:, Folder 79)
    - 1981 May 20 (Box 4:, Folder 80)
    - 1981 May 27 (Box 4:, Folder 81)
    - 1981 June 1 (Box 4:, Folder 82)
    - 1981 June 8 (Box 4:, Folder 83)
    - 1981 June 15 (Box 4:, Folder 84)
    - 1981 June 22 (Box 4:, Folder 85)
    - 1981 July 1 (Box 4:, Folder 86)
    - 1981 July 8 (Box 4:, Folder 87)
    - 1981 July 15 (Box 4:, Folder 88)
    - 1981 July 29 (Box 4:, Folder 89)
    - 1981 August 7 (Box 4:, Folder 90)
    - 1981 August 12-26 (Box 4:, Folder 91)
    - 1981 September 2 (Box 4:, Folder 92)
    - 1981 September 9 (Box 4:, Folder 93)
    - 1981 September 16 (Box 4:, Folder 94)
    - 1981 September 30 (Box 4:, Folder 95)
    - 1981 October 6 (Box 4:, Folder 96)
    - 1981 October 13 (Box 4:, Folder 97)
    - 1981 October 20 (Box 4:, Folder 98)
    - 1981 October 28 (Box 4:, Folder 99)
    - 1981 November 3 (Box 4:, Folder 100)
    - 1981 November 12 (Box 4:, Folder 101)
    - 1981 November 17 (Box 4:, Folder 102)
    - 1981 November 23 (Box 4:, Folder 103)
    - 1981 December 1 (Box 5:, Folder 104)
    - 1981 December 7 (Box 5:, Folder 105)
    - 1981 December 14 (Box 5:, Folder 106)
    - 1981 December 23 (Box 5:, Folder 107)
    - 1982 January 6 (Box 5:, Folder 108)
    - 1982 January 18 (Box 5:, Folder 109)
    - 1982 January 27 (Box 5:, Folder 110)
    - 1982 February 3 (Box 5:, Folder 111)
    - 1982 February 8 (Box 5:, Folder 112)
    - 1982 February 15 (Box 5:, Folder 113)
    - 1982 February 24 (Box 5:, Folder 114)
    - 1982 March 3 (Box 5:, Folder 115)
    - 1982 March 10 (Box 5:, Folder 116)
    - 1982 March 15 (Box 5:, Folder 117)
    - 1982 March 22 (Box 5:, Folder 118)
    - 1982 March 31 (Box 5:, Folder 119)
    - 1982 April 7 (Box 5:, Folder 120)
    - 1982 April 19 (Box 5:, Folder 121)
    - 1982 April 27 (Box 5:, Folder 122)
    - 1982 May 3 (Box 5:, Folder 123)
    - 1982 May 12 (Box 5:, Folder 124)
    - 1982 May 17 (Box 5:, Folder 125)
    - 1982 May 24 (Box 5:, Folder 126)
    - 1982 June 2 (Box 5:, Folder 127)
    - 1982 June 9 (Box 5:, Folder 128)
    - 1982 June 16 (Box 5:, Folder 129)
    - 1982 June 23 (Box 5:, Folder 130)
    - 1982 June 28 (Box 5:, Folder 131)
    - 1982 July 7 (Box 5:, Folder 132)
    - 1982 July 14 (Box 5:, Folder 133)
    - 1982 July 21 (Box 5:, Folder 134)
    - 1982 July 28 - August 4 (Box 5:, Folder 135)
    - 1982 August 11 (Box 5:, Folder 136)
    - 1982 August 24 (Box 5:, Folder 137)
    - 1982 August 30 (Box 5:, Folder 138)
    - 1982 September 3 (Box 5:, Folder 139)
    - 1982 September 7 (Box 5:, Folder 140)
    - 1982 Septmber 17 (Box 5:, Folder 141)
    - 1982 September 20 - October 1 (Box 5:, Folder 142)
    - 1982 October 6 (Box 5:, Folder 143)
    - 1982 October 11 (Box 5:, Folder 144)
    - 1982 October 20 (Box 5:, Folder 145)
    - 1982 October 27 (Box 5:, Folder 146)
    - 1982 November 3 (Box 5:, Folder 147)
    - 1982 Novemer 11 (Box 5:, Folder 148)
    - 1982 December 15 (Box 5:, Folder 149)
    - 1982 December 22 (Box 6:, Folder 150)
    - 1982 December 29 (Box 6:, Folder 151)
    - 1983 January 7 (Box 6:, Folder 152)
    - 1983 January 14 (Box 6:, Folder 153)
    - 1983 January 19 (Box 6:, Folder 154)
    - 1983 January 26 (Box 6:, Folder 155)
    - 1983 January 31 (Box 6:, Folder 156)
    - 1983 February 9 (Box 6:, Folder 157)
    - 1983 February 14 - March 1 (Box 6:, Folder 158)
    - 1983 March 9 (Box 6:, Folder 159)
    - 1983 March 22 (Box 6:, Folder 160)
    - 1983 March 30 (Box 6:, Folder 161)
    - 1983 April 4 (Box 6:, Folder 162)
    - 1983 April 11 (Box 6:, Folder 163)
    - 1983 April 21 (Box 6:, Folder 164)
    - 1983 May 5 (Box 6:, Folder 165)
    - 1983 May 12 (Box 6:, Folder 166)
    - 1983 May 25 (Box 6:, Folder 167)
    - 1983 June 8 (Box 6:, Folder 168)
    - 1983 June 29 (Box 6:, Folder 169)
    - 1983 July 6 (Box 6:, Folder 170)
    - 1983 July 20 (Box 6:, Folder 171)
    - 1983August 3 (Box 6:, Folder 172)
    - 1983 August 8 - 15 (Box 6:, Folder 173)
    - 1983 August 24 (Box 6:, Folder 174)
    - 1983 August 27 (Box 6:, Folder 175)
    - 1983 August 31 (Box 6:, Folder 176)
    - 1983 September 7 (Box 6:, Folder 177)
    - 1983 October 5 (Box 6:, Folder 178)
    - 1983 October 10 (Box 6:, Folder 179)
    - 1983 October 26 (Box 6:, Folder 180)
    - 1983 November 7 (Box 6:, Folder 181)
    - 1983 November 28 (Box 6:, Folder 182)
    - 1983December 14 (Box 6:, Folder 183)
    - 1983 December 21 (Box 6:, Folder 184)
    - 1983 December 28 (Box 7:, Folder 185)
    - 1984 January 4 - 18 (Box 7:, Folder 186)
    - 1984 January 25 (Box 7:, Folder 187)
    - 1984 February 1 (Box 7:, Folder 188)
    - 1984 February 20 (Box 7:, Folder 189)
    - 1984 February 29 (Box 7:, Folder 190)
    - 1984 March 14 (Box 7:, Folder 191)
    - 1984 March 28 (Box 7:, Folder 192)
    - 1984 April 4 (Box 7:, Folder 193)
    - 1984 April 11 (Box 7:, Folder 194)
    - 1984 April 18 (Box 7:, Folder 195)
    - 1984 April 25 (Box 7:, Folder 196)
    - 1984 May 2 (Box 7:, Folder 197)
    - 1984 May 9 (Box 7:, Folder 198)
    - 1984 May 30 (Box 7:, Folder 199)
    - 1984 June 6 (Box 7:, Folder 200)
    - 1984 June 20 (Box 7:, Folder 201)
    - 1984 July 12 (Box 7:, Folder 202)
    - 1984 August 15 (Box 7:, Folder 203)
    - 1984 August 29 (Box 7:, Folder 204)
    - 1984 September 5 (Box 7:, Folder 205)
    - 1984 September 6 (Box 7:, Folder 206)
    - 1984 September 12 (Box 7:, Folder 207)
    - 1984 September 26 (Box 7:, Folder 208)
    - 1984 October 3 (Box 7:, Folder 209)
    - 1984 October 10 (Box 7:, Folder 210)
    - 1984 October 17 (Box 7:, Folder 211)
    - 1984 October 31 (Box 7:, Folder 212)
    - 1984 November 5 - 6 (Box 7:, Folder 213)
    - 1984 November 26 (Box 7:, Folder 214)
    - 1984 December 12 (Box 7:, Folder 215)
    - 1984 December 27 (Box 7:, Folder 216)
    - 1985 January 9 (Box 8:, Folder 219)
    - 1985 January 25 (Box 7:, Folder 217)
    - 1985 February 6 (Box 7:, Folder 218)
    - 1985 February 27 (Box 8:, Folder 220)
    - 1985 March 6 (Box 8:, Folder 221)
    - 1985 March 13 (Box 8:, Folder 222)
    - 1985 March 20 (Box 8:, Folder 223)
    - 1985 March 27 (Box 8:, Folder 224)
    - 1985 April 3 (Box 8:, Folder 225)
    - 1985 April 10 (Box 8:, Folder 226-227)
    - 1985 April 17 (Box 8:, Folder 228)
    - 1985 April 24 (Box 8:, Folder 229)
    - 1985 May 1 (Box 8:, Folder 230)
    - 1985 May 8 (Box 8:, Folder 231)
    - 1985 May 15 (Box 8:, Folder 232)
    - 1985 May 29 (Box 8:, Folder 233)
    - 1985 June 6 (Box 8:, Folder 234)
    - 1985 July 2 (Box 8:, Folder 235)
    - 1985 July 7 (Box 8:, Folder 236)
    - 1985 August 7 (Box 8:, Folder 237)
    - 1985 August 14 (Box 8:, Folder 238)
    - 1985 August 21 (Box 8:, Folder 239)
    - 1985 August 28 (Box 8:, Folder 240)
    - 1985 September 4 (Box 8:, Folder 241)
    - 1985 September 11 (Box 8:, Folder 242)
    - 1985 September 12 (Box 8:, Folder 243)
    - 1985 September 18 (Box 8:, Folder 244)
    - 1985 September 25 (Box 8:, Folder 245)
    - 1985 October 2 (Box 8:, Folder 246)
    - 1985 October 9 (Box 8:, Folder 247)
    - 1985 October 16 (Box 8:, Folder 248)
    - 1985 October 30 (Box 8:, Folder 249)
    - 1985 November 6 (Box 8:, Folder 250)
    - 1985 November 13 (Box 8:, Folder 251)
    - 1985 November 20 (Box 8:, Folder 252)
    - 1985 November 27 (Box 8:, Folder 253)
    - 1985 December 11 (Box 8:, Folder 254)
    - 1986 January 8 (Box 9:, Folder 255)
    - 1986 January 22 (Box 9:, Folder 256)
    - 1986 February 5 (Box 9:, Folder 257)
    - 1986 February 12 (Box 9:, Folder 258)
    - 1986 February 19 (Box 9:, Folder 259)
    - 1986 March 5 (Box 9:, Folder 260)
    - 1986 March 12 (Box 9:, Folder 261)
    - 1986 March 19 (Box 9:, Folder 262)
    - 1986 April 9 (Box 9:, Folder 263)
    - 1986 April 16 (Box 9:, Folder 264)
    - 1986 April 28 (Box 9:, Folder 265)
    - 1986 May 14 (Box 9:, Folder 266)
    - 1986 May 21 (Box 9:, Folder 267)
    - 1986 May 28 (Box 9:, Folder 268)
    - 1986 June 4 (Box 9:, Folder 269)
    - 1986 June 25 (Box 9:, Folder 270)
    - 1986 July 2 (Box 9:, Folder 271)
    - 1986 July 30 (Box 9:, Folder 272)
    - 1986 August 13 (Box 9:, Folder 273)
    - 1986 August 27 (Box 9:, Folder 274)
    - 1986 September 3 (Box 9:, Folder 275)
    - 1986 September 10 (Box 9:, Folder 276)
    - 1986 September 17 (Box 9:, Folder 277)
    - 1986 September 24 (Box 9:, Folder 278)
    - 1986 October 1 (Box 9:, Folder 279)
    - 1986 October 15 (Box 9:, Folder 280)
    - 1986 October 22 (Box 9:, Folder 281)
    - 1986 November 5 (Box 9:, Folder 282)
    - 1986 November 12 (Box 9:, Folder 283)
    - 1986 November 19 (Box 9:, Folder 284)
    - 1986 December 3 (Box 9:, Folder 285)
    - 1986 December 11 (Box 9:, Folder 286)
    - 1986 December 17 (Box 9:, Folder 287)
    - 1986 (Box 9:, Folder 288)
    - 1987 January 14 (Box 9:, Folder 289)
    - 1987 January 21 (Box 9:, Folder 290)
    - 1987 January 28 (Box 9:, Folder 291)
    - 1987 February 26 (Box 9:, Folder 292)
    - 1987 March 5 (Box 9:, Folder 293)
    - 1987 March 25 (Box 9:, Folder 294)
    - 1987 April 1 (Box 9:, Folder 295)
    - 1987 April 6 (Box 9:, Folder 296)
    - 1987 April 15 (Box 9:, Folder 297)
    - 1987 April 22 (Box 9:, Folder 298)
    - 1987 May 13 (Box 9:, Folder 299)
    - 1987 May 20 (Box 9:, Folder 299a)
    - 1987 May 27 (Box 9:, Folder 300)
    - 1987 June 3 (Box 9:, Folder 301)
    - 1987 June 17 (Box 9:, Folder 302)
    - 1987 June 25 (Box 9:, Folder 303)
    - 1987 July 8 (Box 10:, Folder 304)
    - 1987 July 15 (Box 10:, Folder 305)
    - 1987 July 28 (Box 10:, Folder 306)
    - 1987 August 5 (Box 10:, Folder 307)
    - 1987 August 12 (Box 10:, Folder 308)
    - 1987 August 26 (Box 10:, Folder 309)
    - 1987 September 2 (Box 10:, Folder 310)
    - 1987 September 9 (Box 10:, Folder 311)
    - 1987 September 16 (Box 10:, Folder 312)
    - 1987 September 23 (Box 10:, Folder 313)
    - 1987 October 7 (Box 10:, Folder 314)
    - 1987 October 14 (Box 10:, Folder 315)
    - 1987 October 21 (Box 10:, Folder 316)
    - 1987 November 3 (Box 10:, Folder 317)
    - 1987 November 18 (Box 10:, Folder 318)
    - 1987 December 16 (Box 10:, Folder 319)
    - 1987 (Box 10:, Folder 320)
    - 1988 January 13 (Box 10:, Folder 321)
    - 1988 January 27 (Box 10:, Folder 322)
    - 1988 February 17 (Box 10:, Folder 323)
    - 1988 February 24 (Box 10:, Folder 324)
    - 1988 March 9 (Box 10:, Folder 325)
    - 1988 April 6 (Box 10:, Folder 326)
    - 1988 April 13 (Box 10:, Folder 327)
    - 1988 April 20 (Box 10:, Folder 328)
    - 1988 June 8 (Box 10:, Folder 329)
    - 1988 June 22 (Box 10:, Folder 330)
    - 1988 August 17 (Box 10:, Folder 331)
    - 1988 August 24 (Box 10:, Folder 332)
    - 1988 August 31 (Box 10:, Folder 333)
    - 1988 September 6 (Box 10:, Folder 334)
    - 1988 September 13 (Box 10:, Folder 335)
    - 1988 September 23 (Box 10:, Folder 336)
    - 1988 October 4 (Box 10:, Folder 337)
    - 1988 October 12 (Box 10:, Folder 338)
    - 1988 October 26 (Box 10:, Folder 339)
    - 1988 NOvember 16 (Box 10:, Folder 340)
    - 1988 November 30 (Box 10:, Folder 341)
    - 1988 December 8 (Box 10:, Folder 342)
    - 1988 December 16 (Box 10:, Folder 343)
    - 1988 December 21 (Box 10:, Folder 344)
    - 1989 January 4 (Box 11:, Folder 346)
    - 1989 February 1 (Box 11:, Folder 347)
    - 1989 February 15 (Box 11:, Folder 348)
    - 1989 March 1 (Box 11:, Folder 349)
    - 1989 March 15 (Box 11:, Folder 350)
    - 1989 April 6 (Box 11:, Folder 351)
    - 1989 April 19 (Box 11:, Folder 352)
    - 1989 May 3 (Box 11:, Folder 353)
    - 1989 May 17 (Box 11:, Folder 354)
    - 1989 June 8 (Box 11:, Folder 355)
    - 1989 June 21 (Box 11:, Folder 356)
    - 1989 July 18 (Box 11:, Folder 357)
    - 1989 August 1 (Box 11:, Folder 358)
    - 1989 August 16 (Box 11:, Folder 359)
    - 1989 September 27 (Box 11:, Folder 360)
    - 1989 October 23 (Box 11:, Folder 361)
    - 1989 December 20 (Box 11:, Folder 362)
    - 1989 (Box 11:, Folder 363)
    - 1990 February 14 (Box 11:, Folder 364)
    - 1990 April 11 (Box 11:, Folder 365)
    - 1990 May 23 (Box 11:, Folder 366)
    - 1990 June 13 (Box 11:, Folder 367)
    - 1990 (Box 11:, Folder 368)